<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Guideline on Master Pi</title>
    <link>https://masterpi-2124.github.io/categories/guideline/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Guideline on Master Pi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://masterpi-2124.github.io/categories/guideline/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How I Setup My Development Environment</title>
      <link>https://masterpi-2124.github.io/p/how-i-setup-my-development-environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 21:54:03 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://masterpi-2124.github.io/p/how-i-setup-my-development-environment/</guid>
      <description>Hi, this is my quick guideline on how to improve linux development experience.
Operating system When you search for &amp;ldquo;Linux OS&amp;rdquo;, Google would give you thousands of &amp;ldquo;operation systems&amp;rdquo; like Ubuntu, Arch, Mint, &amp;hellip; So which one is best for you?
First, &amp;ldquo;Linux&amp;rdquo; as you say is not &amp;ldquo;operating system&amp;rdquo;. It is the kernel, the bridge between software and hardware, and reponsible for almost everything in the computer. When you boot your computer, it is the first part of the OS loaded into the RAM for your system to start working.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Make Your Trackpad Like Macbook</title>
      <link>https://masterpi-2124.github.io/p/how-to-make-your-trackpad-like-macbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://masterpi-2124.github.io/p/how-to-make-your-trackpad-like-macbook/</guid>
      <description>If you used Mac products before, I bet the only thing you will never forget is its multi-touch trackpad. Its convenience can improve the work performance a lot, and it even made me feel confused when using other products&amp;rsquo;s trackpad. Luckily, when you say &amp;ldquo;Linux&amp;rdquo;, you are talking about the &amp;ldquo;Open Sources&amp;rdquo;, and there are some drivers that support it, like mtrack.
In this blog, we will dive into how we can make our trackpad as close to Mac experience as we can get with mtrack.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Make a Github Blog</title>
      <link>https://masterpi-2124.github.io/p/how-to-make-a-github-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://masterpi-2124.github.io/p/how-to-make-a-github-blog/</guid>
      <description>Hi, this is my way to make a Github blog for my self, which will contain blogs, some projects, and some tips from my experience. I am a webasite newbie, so it took me almost 2 days to setup from start to finish, and it&amp;rsquo;s pretty easy. Here is how I made it.
Initial setup Create repositories First, let take a look at what a Github Page is, and how to create one.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
